hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so now uh we are going to talk
about a problem which is very common
across uh different projects or teams
which is the problem of uh unattended
execution which means uh you don't uh
execute your automated test manually
because it defeats the purpose of
automation okay so you build your
automated test but then you end up
running them manually which is a waste
of resources and time so every
automation project no matter if you're
using tosa or you are not using tosa you
should have some kind of unattended
execution which means you should be able
ble to schedule your automated test to
run without any manual interruption or
without any manual efforts right so that
should be unattended it should not be
done by a person sitting behind a desk
and manually executing the test and
looking at those tests right so all this
process should be automated now there
are multiple ways to schedule this uh
test executions one way is obviously
viously you can use a cicd tool but what
if you don't have any cicd integration
or you don't have access to these tools
then you can always fall back upon your
windows scheduler which is a window
based tool which can schedule any
particular events and we can use this
Windows scheduler to uh schedule our
executions from tosa Commander so I'm
going to show you how we can do that uh
we already know about TC shell right so
this is the command line tool for tosa
through which you can do different tasks
without even opening tosa commander and
we are going to use the same method to
uh schedule execution from the windows
scheduler
okay so for this um I have already
prepared a TC shell okay script so if I
open this it is in the format. TCS so
whenever you are creating any tcell
script it will be in the format of TCS
which is the extension right now uh what
I'm doing here so I'm using this tcsl
commands so first one is to jump to node
okay so what node it does it is going
into the execution folder then into
execution list and then into this swag
Labs folder and then it is going into
this run login okay when um I look at
this so this is the jump to node which
will basically uh jump to this
particular node okay and then uh there
is a task command which is to clear the
log then there is a task to run the
execution and then there's a task to
save the results okay so these are all
the tasks which this particular script
will
perform now the next uh thing here is
the batch file okay so this is the batch
command which will be
executed and if we go ahead and look at
it so if you look at edit a notepad so
here uh it is first going into the
commander home directory okay so there
is a CD command and then this is uh the
T Cell workspace command where we are
trying to open the workspace okay so
this is the workspace file path and then
we are providing the login credentials
for us it is a local workspace so it is
got no login credentials and then we are
passing uh the parameter which is the
script okay so c training tcell script.
DCS which is the path of the file so
this is the batch command which will be
used for triggering the execution okay
and this batch command will be uh
triggered from the windows schedule
right now uh we will go to the windows
scheduler okay for that um I'm going to
search for that okay so task
scheduler and here is the task scheduler
so we will open this we will go to the
task scheduler Library okay and from the
right hand side there is an actions tab
so from here we will click on create
task uh here we will provide it a name
so we will say tosa
executions okay so
execution
for
tosa automated test okay so I'll give it
a name and description then here uh we
will run this with highest privileges
okay then we'll go to the triggers tab
here click on
new and now we will um begin the tasks
so you can see there are lots of
different options right so we will keep
it on a
schedule um we'll keep it one time so I
will keep it after just 2 minutes okay
so that we see it uh
running so let me make
it
okay and then there are advanced
settings you can delay theask for random
delay you can repeat the task uh every 1
hour or
duration um and then you can expire and
stop task okay so these are okay uh
we'll click on okay so our trigger is
now enabled now we will go to actions uh
we will click on new we will choose the
action as start a program
and then uh we'll choose the program
script here okay so here we will choose
the execute batch
Command right and now we will click on
okay and click on okay and now we will
verify in the schedule Library whether
our uh event is being displayed here or
not right so you can see tosa executions
uh status is ready triggered at this
time on this date okay and it will also
show you the next run time here so this
is the next run
time and now we just need to wait for
this to trigger the execution okay so
it'll trigger it after 2 minutes um what
I can also do is I can basically right
click on this and I can start the run
right away okay or I can wait for uh it
to execute at the given
time so let's uh wait for this uh to
trigger the event okay okay so as you
can see U the Windows command uh it
opened on its own and it started to run
all the commands which we have provided
in that batch Command right so uh it is
now currently running but the problem is
I have kept the workspace open right so
uh it will not execute until I close the
workspace because it cannot log in into
the workspace right because it is open
locally so I'm going to close my
workspace
now and here uh now we are going to say
no okay um so to show you uh I'm going
to change the time of this particular uh
execution so what we are going to do is
we are going to go to
properties and we are going to triggers
we will go and edit this trigger and we
will try to trigger it again
okay and we keep it zero click on okay
and okay okay so now we will wait for it
to trigger this particular execution
this time it should run because I have
closed the workspace
so always remember that whenever you are
running anything from TC shell uh then
your workspace should be closed if
you're trying to open it from your
command line okay so as you can see uh
it started the command prompt on its own
I did not uh started it and it all also
started the execution now so it is
basically running the bad script in the
background so it will complete this
execution and then um it will perform
all the tasks and uh it will end uh the
event okay so whatever we have scheduled
will run on its own you can do it on a
daily basis you can do it on a weekly
basis or you can do it on um any time
you like right so this is a powerful uh
scheduling tool okay you don't need to
always depend on a cicd tool uh if you
don't have a cicd integrated in your
project you can still uh do unattended
execution automatically using the Tas
scheduler which is part of your windows
uh operating
system that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video